hello guys it's me nikki hey a couple of
weeks ago over on twitter at
nikkietutorials if you're not following
me someone created this conversation
about how this like soft beat is so
popular right now you see it on all the
like influencers you see it on all the
celebrities and it's a type of makeup
look where
it looks
natural in a very glam and extra way and
in that tweet someone said that i
couldn't do that
just imagine me being on my phone like
this like oh my god he has hell oh my
god yeah girl that is a good nicki can't
do it okay
so when i saw that i was like you know
what i haven't done an in-depth makeup
tutorial in so long so today we are
going back to our roots sitting down and
playing with makeup and i'm doing so in
collaboration with marc jacobs beauty as
you know i am their global artistry
advisor so this video is in
collaboration with them to showcase you
a couple of products that i've been
really really liking and that i'm super
proud of that they came out with so if
you're excited about the good old makeup
days and if you actually want to see if
i'm able to do a perfect soft beat like
that then keep on watching
alrighty let the in-depth tutorial
commence the first product i really want
to talk about is youthquake this is a
brand new product to marc jacobs and i'm
really really liking it because i worked
with it back at new york fashion week
when i joined the marc jacobs beauty
team to do makeup backstage at fashion
week it is a moisturizer that
it's a moisturizer that perfectly preps
the skin for all the paint whenever i
plan on doing my makeup and my skin is
feeling a little bit dry i like to go in
with this really work it in and get that
moisture back it like creates the
perfect canvas so in here our pineapple
enzymes that retexturize and
re-moisturize the skin now moving on to
primer primer is really essential if you
want your makeup to last and before marc
jacobs have this product right here this
is the undercover invisible perfecting
coconut primer so now they came out with
this right here this is the undercover
blurring coconut primer so this is great
at hiding the appearance of your pores
you know it evens up the texture it
gives you that veil of blurriness and it
controls oils meaning that it will keep
your makeup on longer and making it look
flawless till the end of the day so i
like to take just a tiny bit of this you
definitely don't need a lot and i kind
of tap it into the skin tap tap and it
creates that blurry filter and it smells
amazing it smells like coconut so if you
love coconuts you are in for a party but
why i like this so much is usually when
it comes to like blurring primers they
become super matte which is a good thing
because that will keep your makeup on
longer but they also dry out my skin and
i have the type of skin that dries out
very quickly i have combination skin and
this thank god doesn't do that for me so
thank god i collaborated with the brand
that like gets it but see especially my
nose it looks blurred
it looks like there's a filter on top of
it okay so the ground work has been done
i'm primed i am ready for all the makeup
i'm ready for all the paint let's go in
with foundation now i you guys know i
love this one this is by makeup
revolution it is the conceal and defined
foundation that is the foundation i'm
going to be going in with today just
full coverage it looks like skin it
looks beautiful now a little trick since
summertime is here you can add in a
couple of luminizing drops and i think
it's fun to let you know that if you
love the marc jacobs dewdrops in do you
there is a brand new color for my dark
skin divas out there this is the new
color look at that is a lot more tan a
lot more deep this is tantalized okay
let's start working that into the skin
and make sure that if you want full
coverage from your product to tap
that sponge onto the skin so no smearing
no dragging
up and down short tapping motions and
look at that
oh
it's got a beautiful healthy shine to it
the skin is looking right
the forehead baby because my forehead
has been a problem area but it's i woke
up this morning and it cleared up a lot
so i was like okay this is a good makeup
day honey
oh yeah look at that base honey look at
the base
i love makeup so much for concealer
today i'm using the elf flawless
concealer
so i always start tapping the bottom of
the concealer first
to make sure that everything that's like
sort of on my cheeks is blended to
perfection like that look at that ooh
flawless and then you look up and you
barely tap underneath the eye
so you get the most coverage hey jackie
i know thank you for the tip honey
barely tap the under eye like straight
to the lashes
so it remains the most coverage ever and
then i'm gonna set everything using my
fenty beauty pro filter powder and
butter
i quickly went off camera to do my brows
and to do the first eye and as you can
see it is a very smoky sculpted
summer any like any season really type
of look i mean when you look at all the
inspiration one thing that really speaks
to me is that overall the look is very
matte when it comes to the eyes there's
a lot of bronziness going on on the skin
and a lot of dew and glow but when it
comes to the eyes it is fairly
matte and very sculpted and now remember
miss tutorials over here has hooded eyes
and i love this technique because you go
beyond the lines you go beyond the skin
and sculpt your own dream really so
let's start it off let's optimus prime
the palette i'll be dipping into today
is by colourpop and becky g and this is
salvaje and i'm going in with this color
right here and that is called carmelo
and with this we're going to build our
structure i pick up that color on a
morphe m433 brush
and i start placing it i look straight
into my mirror so not like down or up i
look straight into my mirror and i place
that color on the outside of my crease
but above my crease this is the first
step if you're following your own
natural lines
if you have hooded eyes like i do it's
it's all just gonna fall down and
nobody's gonna see it so we gotta go in
and create our own height so i look
forward and i go above where my natural
crease is
and i start stamping in that color now
like i said this look is very sculpted
so i'm also bringing it onto the lid and
blending it in towards the eye
more towards the lash line for a smoky
liner look then i go ahead pick up more
and place it right here on that outer
corner cover that entire lid and now you
see that the outer portion of your eye
is completely covered but we need to
find our angle and i think the best
angle for like a winged out sculpted
shape like this is by just following the
water line so like right there
just stamping it in
going up into that crease okay now that
you've got that outer corner down it is
time to build more structure
in your crease
so just softly i pick up more of that
color and i start bringing it in
towards the center of my eye
just using
soft circular motions i'm barely
touching the skin and see we're going in
baby i'm bringing it in but almost
slanting up
towards like this portion of the brow
we're we're basically hitting that so
we're going up up up honey then we're
going to do something scary but have
faith
we're talking about makeup here but half
faith we're going to go up
onto that brow to like the the first
third of the brow and then down towards
this portion of
sort of like the the side of the nose
bridge
so basically the shape is like going out
like a cat shape
into the crease up to that brow down
towards this portion here does that make
any sense the most scary part is getting
it into that brow i'm blending into my
brow
and bringing it towards this nose line
we call it here
now a little trick is to sort of like
smush it into the front of the brow so
you know where you're going
little circles into the front of the
brow brushing downwards do the magic for
you then i pick up a morphe m562
and i'm placing that brush flat against
my skin
and from that sort of structure
you want to kind of stretch above it to
create your fade
this by holding the brush like this
against the cheek and sort of like
waving at the blend
you're giving it that soft haze i'm
barely touching the skin too and for
this outer corner here since we're doing
that pulled out shape
you can really softly
fade that out from that same palette i'm
taking the dark brown called cafeto cafe
i don't know what that means but i'm
saying it and one thing i've definitely
also noticed is that the outer corner
and the lash line are like a smoky
sultry dark wrap and just dropped a
brush so i'm definitely going to use
that color to darken that outer portion
up a bit kind of tapping it on as soon
as you take a dark color like this and
you start swirling it onto the eye you
will have fall out for days honey so be
cautious stamping it on blending it into
the mix and getting the drama see oh yes
yes yes like
okay for the lid i'm not taking luna
that matte white sort of like really
like beige light shade and you can opt
for a shimmery shade here i just love
the beauty of having an all matte eye
with this type of look i don't know it's
it's like really hitting all the feels
for me
so i'm just setting that portion that we
haven't really done much with yet with
this shade you can go all the way up and
kind of reinforce
the contrast between light and dark see
what i'm doing i'm giving it back that
height
now i'm taking that dark brown color
cafecito
and i'm stamping it on to where i would
normally apply a liquid liner so onto
the lash line
and this creates for a very soft but
effective
smoked out lash line then for the lower
lash line i take caramelo and i just
stamp it on
and don't drag it in too far because
with a lot of the shapes on the bottom
i'm seeing a lot of darkness towards the
corner and then as it fades in on the
lower lash line it becomes lighter and
lighter
so i'm definitely
channeling that so now that i'm reaching
that outer corner here i'm going in with
cafecito
and bringing the sculpted drama
i think it is super important to
connect the lower lash line to the outer
corner here
to make it one
another brush just went down
and then another thing i think is vital
to this look is opening up the waterline
using a nude or white pencil my favorite
is by colourpop the cream gel liner and
this one is in the color honey dude
okay that is it sculpting wise and
shadow wise now pop on your favorite
pair of lashes and bottom mascara and
i'll be right back all right time for
the cheeks and the face portion is
really really important to this look
because when you look at all the
inspiration a lot of structure is
happening on the eyes but even more
structure is happening on the face so
i'm going in with my marc jacobs bronzer
in tantric but i do want to let you know
that along with the dewdrops there also
now is a deeper shade of bronzer this is
also in the shade tantalize and uh yeah
dark skin divas hello so a lot of the
warmth is happening around here so the
forehead is sculpted to to the heavens
and a lot of warmth is almost on the
spots where you would highlight so that
is what we're doing today grabbing my
marc jacobs bronzer and then
really high up like i'm on my
highlighting spot
i started swirling in
that warmth
you don't want to take it too far in
about like halfway
of the cheeks but keep it high up baby
and then if you have a large forehead 10
head like i do you're gonna love this
trend because we are here to cut it in
half
guys how do you feel about the in-depth
sort of makeup tutorial that i'm doing
today it um it brings me back i feel
like i don't do them as much anymore
because there's basically not a lot of
demand for it so i hope that you guys
are liking it even if it's just a little
less of a bunch than usual so yeah let
me know how you think these videos are
and if you still enjoy them one super
important thing is to contour the nose
like nobody's business
a contoured perfected nose in this look
is vital so i take my brush that has my
bronzer and i just kind of scratch it
over it to give myself that warmth i i
just focus on getting that color and
that shape first and i will
focus about the shape after once i start
carving it out but it's missing that
connection from that inner portion to
the nose contour so i take a fluffy
brush and i just connect
that inner portion of the eye to the
nose
to give myself that structure so like i
said now it just looks like warmth now
just looks like a blob of bronzer on the
nose so i'm gonna take a face powder and
a dry beauty sponge and carve out the
sides and the top to give it shape
so i almost come from that inner corner
and drag it onto the sides
of my nose so inner corner
drag it down
and i'm also going to take a little bit
and apply it right here
on the bridge
to get that to see and now you've got a
very sculpted nose but of course you
don't want to leave it like this that's
a
little a little extreme so i take a big
face brush and i kind of dust away
the edges and that leaves you with a
perfectly contoured snatched nose
without all the fuss without like
drawing lines and blending out the lines
it's a quick way to get a perfect
snatched
nose now going in with a whisper of
mac's blush in peaches and also more up
towards the side not really on the apple
we're really creating this like slanted
structured
face
so more towards where the bronzer is too
for highlighter today i'm going in with
the wet and wild mega glow highlighter
in bloom time
oh
deadly you know that sort of dew is
always going on so i'm also popping the
slightest bit on my forehead
on the chin
and of course i'm gonna do the tip of my
nose
now it's time for another iconic portion
of the look over drawn penciled nude
glossy lips you see them on everybody
lip pencil has really made its comeback
and we're all using it to just create
the illusion so i'm going in with the
makeup forever artist pencil in anywhere
caffeine it's one of my favorites
because i love the tone and i love the
the formula of these pencils now what
i'm seeing a lot is that a lot of
artists just
create like a half circle here at the
cupid's bow i don't necessarily like
that look on me it's a little too much
because i've got my lip fillers going on
it's like it's like a lot okay it's a
lot but i do love to kind of go over the
edge when lining my lips to give myself
that extra pout so i always pull my lip
in like this like huh and then i just
kind of create the mcdonald's sign on my
cupid's bow
like that now of course he can go bigger
you can create that half circle right
here but i
like it like this now i'm just going to
frame the lip
for lipstick i'm taking the kkw beauty
nude lipstick and number one
you want this to be nude honey
so i definitely bring it up to
that lip liner
i think it's weird if you just stay
below it and it's sort of just like
sitting there
so
blend this in with the contours you just
apply to those lips and oh do you see
the fantasy coming along
now i will say you either love that look
or you hate it i feel like there's no in
between i obviously love it i'm really
excited about this marc jacobs beauty
has come out with a special edition
glitter colored enamored lip glosses
enamored with pride it comes in a
special pride packaging and this color
right here is
this color here is called pink parade
and look at that glitter look at that
shine it's gonna go perfect with this
glossy nude lip trend and for gloss
definitely bring it all the way
to the edge
[Music]
boom some setting spray and we're done
and that is it guys i feel like this is
one of the very highly demanded looks
that i see going around lately and i
absolutely love it and to that one
person on twitter that said that i
couldn't do it
hi it was also great to be able to
showcase you a couple of the new marc
jacobs beauty products available at
marcjacosbeauty.com and sephora.com so
uh yeah without any further ado let's go
on to the dutch word of the day
for today i thought it was pretty
difficult but i came up with one sultry
that eye look you've got going on is so
school if you want to be featured in my
next video all you have to do is leave a
comment down below featuring the dutch
word of the day or leave a video
response on instagram under the hashtag
dutchword of the day i want to thank you
so much for watching i hope you enjoyed
let me know if you want more in-depth
makeup tutorials back on my channel and
i love you and hopefully i will see you
guys on the next one bye